[
 {
      "question":"Which of the following Sectarian symbols appeared on the royal prashastis, coins, and seals?lingaTrishulaBullChakraSelect the correct option from the codes given below:",
      "optionA":"Only 1 & 2",
      "optionB":"Only 1 & 3",
      "optionC":"Only 1, 2 & 3",
      "optionD":"1, 2, 3 & 4.",
      "correctAns":"1, 2, 3 & 4."
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following period saw the emergence of worship of composite deities such as Hari-Hara?",
      "optionA":"Magadha period",
      "optionB":"Gupta period",
      "optionC":"Kushana period",
      "optionD":"Mauryan Period",
      "correctAns":"Gupta period"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following Dharmashastra is a book on statecraft?",
      "optionA":"Katyayana",
      "optionB":"Yajnavalkya",
      "optionC":"Nitisara",
      "optionD":"Narada",
      "correctAns":"Nitisara"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following period saw the emergence of worship of composite deities such as Hari-Hara?",
      "optionA":"Magadha period",
      "optionB":"Gupta period",
      "optionC":"Kushana period",
      "optionD":"Mauryan Period",
      "correctAns":"Gupta period"
   },
   {
      "question":"Vata-bhuta refers to which of the following?",
      "optionA":"Plough tax",
      "optionB":"King’s customary share of the produce normally amounting to one-sixth of the produce, paid by all cultivators.",
      "optionC":"Cesses for the maintenance of rites performed for the winds and spirits.",
      "optionD":"None of the above",
      "correctAns":"Cesses for the maintenance of rites performed for the winds and spirits"
   },
   {
      "question":"Halivakara refers to which of the following?",
      "optionA":"Irrigation tax",
      "optionB":"Plough tax",
      "optionC":"Crop tax",
      "optionD":"House tax",
      "correctAns":"Plough tax"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following kings is considered as the founder of the Vakataka empire?",
      "optionA":"Pravarasena I",
      "optionB":"Pravarasena II",
      "optionC":"Vindhyasakti",
      "optionD":"Rudrasena II",
      "correctAns":"Vindhyasakti"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following assumed the title of ‘Siladitya’?",
      "optionA":"Harsha Vardhan",
      "optionB":"Rajya Vardhana",
      "optionC":"Prabhakar Vardhana",
      "optionD":"None of the above",
      "correctAns":"Harsha Vardhan"
   },
   {
      "question":"The capital of Harsha was shifted from Thaneswar to which of the following?",
      "optionA":"Kannauj",
      "optionB":"Mathura",
      "optionC":"Ujjain",
      "optionD":"Kalinga",
      "correctAns":"Kannau"
   },
   {
      "question":"The magistrates who looked after towns and cities in Mauryan empire were known as?",
      "optionA":"Nagaradhyaksha",
      "optionB":"Baladhyakshas",
      "optionC":"Adhyakshas",
      "optionD":"Amatyas",
      "correctAns":"Nagaradhyaksha"
   }
]